<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>A Case Study of Conservation in the Abitibi Region - Qu&#233;bec/Ontario Border - Final Report</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name type="corporate">
    <namePart>AborVitae Environmental Service</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">Author</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <genre>working paper</genre>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>2004-06-21</dateCreated>
    <publisher>National Round Table on the Environment and the Economy</publisher>
  </originInfo>
  <language>
    <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <identifier type="local">RPT_AES_A-Case-Study-of-Conservation-in-the-Abitibi-Region-Quebec-Ontario-Border-Final-Report.pdf</identifier>
  <abstract>The National Round Table on the Environment and the Economy (NRTEE), through its &#8220;Conservation of Natural Heritage&#8221; program, is exploring the status of conservation and identifying key challenges and opportunities at the national level in Canada. Through its Conserving Canada&#8217;s Natural Capital: the Boreal Forest&#8221; program, NRTEE is examining how to advance conservation on the working boreal forest landscape. The Abitibi region case study is one of three conducted across the Boreal Forest in Canada.</abstract>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <part>
      <extent>51 p.</extent>
    </part>
  </relatedItem>
  <location>
    <url>http://warming.apps01.yorku.ca/library/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/NRTEE-2004-A-Case-Study-of-Conservation-in-the-Abitibi-Region-Qu%C3%A9becOntario-Border.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <subject>
    <topic>Boreal forest</topic>
  </subject>
  <accessCondition>&#169; This Work is protected by copyright and made available for personal or public non-commercial use and may be reproduced, in part or in whole, and by any means, and may be further distributed for non-commercial use, without charge or further permission. All users are required to indicate that the reproduction, in part or in whole, is a copy of a Work of the National Round Table on the Environment and the Economy (NRTEE). Reproduction, in whole or in part, of this Work for the purpose of commercial redistribution is strictly prohibited. Furthermore, no right to modify or alter in any manner the Work is hereby granted.</accessCondition>
</mods>
