<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Letter to Mrs. Stepler from Gordon Stepler, August 31st 1916</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name type="personal">
    <affiliation>Canadian Armed Forces</affiliation>
    <namePart>Stepler, Gordon</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">Correspondent</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name type="personal">
    <namePart>Stepler, Ethelwyn</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">Correspondent</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
  <genre authority="marcgt">Letter</genre>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>1916-08-31</dateCreated>
    <place>
      <placeTerm authority="marccountry">England</placeTerm>
    </place>
    <dateOther>31 August 1916</dateOther>
  </originInfo>
  <language>
    <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <abstract>Consists of a letter written by Gordon Stepler to his mother, Mrs. Ethelwyn Stepler. Transcription is as follows:&#13;
Shorncliffe, Aug 31/16&#13;
&#13;
Dear Mother,&#13;
	Well I am back at camp again. I had the time of my life on my leave but it was rotten coming back to camp again and makes the life here seem a lot worse. The best part of it was having  decent meals and a good bed to sleep on.&#13;
	I found Margaret's cake waiting for me and two letters, one from Verna and one from Bessie when I got back. Peggy sent a swell fruit cake and my it was good. The parcel you sent arrived this morning and you may be sure I was glad to get it. It arrived in perfect condition but I was sorry the postage was so much. You showed good taste in what you put in it as everything was just what I wanted. A "Life" also came.&#13;
|page 2&#13;
There was no name on it but I suppose it was from Miss Meekinson.&#13;
	I wrote you two or three letters on the way but in case I left out anything I suppose I might as well start from the beginning. Well, Harcourt, Caverhill, Colbeck, Coliton, Steele and myself left here on last Wednesday noon. We arrived in London about half past three and as our train did not leave for Glasgow until eleven o'clock we had some time to see the city. We first took a ride on a bus. They didn't have street cars in the central part of the city but double decked motor buses. They have girl conductors and they looked real snappy in their uniforms. We rode around by High Park to King's Cross and then got off. We went through Westminster Abbey. It&#13;
|page 3&#13;
was very beautiful and we saw where all the kings and queens were buried, etc. We then saw Buckingham Palace. I was disappointed in it and did not think much of it. We also saw the Parliament Buildings, Queen Victoria's monument, Nelson's monument and London Bridge. By this time it was time for something to eat so we had a good meal. In the evening we went to the "Duke of Yorks" theatre and saw "Daddy Long Legs." [It was] fine. We took a taxi to the station but got separated in the crowd but thought we would meet at the train. Harcourt and I took the underground to Euston Station as that is the fastest way of travelling but we just missed it. Colbeck and Coliton got it but we&#13;
|page 4&#13;
did not see anything of Caverhill &amp; Stule till at the station coming back. Harcourt and I stayed in London all night and took the train in the morning. We arrived in Glasgow at 6.15 pouring rain. We went to a hotel first and then to the Glasgow "Alhambra" theatre and saw a good vaudeville show. First thing next morning we met Coliton and Colbeck so we were very lucky. The next morning we went to Edinburgh. It was raining so we first went to a hotel. Then we went to Edinburgh Castle. It is an old large castle built of stone on a steep rock and in the olden days must have been almost impregnable. There were old cannon and all the old fashioned implements of war in it also points of interest as Queen Mary's bedroom, the smallest chapel in Scotland - St. Margaret's - and other things. We then walked down through an&#13;
|page 5&#13;
[?] rather poor part of the city, by the John Knox house to Holywood Castle. It is where the old kings and queens of Scotland used to live. It contained many interesting things of historic importance. We then walked along Prince's Street which is the prettiest street I ever saw, as it is one of the most beautiful in the world, passed Scott's monument which is over 200 ft high and very elaborate, to the Royal Scottish Museum. We went in and saw the statues, paintings and other works of art. It is one of the best collections in the world. The original cartoons of the war by the famous Louis Raemaekers were there. By this time I was late so we went back, had lunch and went to a theatre in the evening. The next morning we went back to Glasgow in time to take the boat trip down the Clyde in the "Isle of Arran." The first part down was through all the dockyards and the greatest ship-building plant in the&#13;
|page 6&#13;
world. All kinds of boats were there. you could see battleships, big merchantmen, destroyers, submarines etc, in all stages of completion - from first a framework to the finished article. We had a good dinner on the boat and reached the town of Dunoon about half past one and had an hour ashore. It is an old fashioned old Scotch town where they had not seen many Canadians and we were sort of looked upon as curiosities. It's as far down the Clyde as pleasure boats are allowed to go for fear of subs and we then took a cruise through the lochs. The scenery was wonderful. The lochs were deep and narrow and high hills rose on each side. Most of them were covered with purple heather and many of them were rocky. Some had an old castle on top where some old lord used to reside. After seeing the Gareloch we came back via Dunoon, had afternoon tea and supper on the boat, and got into Glasgow again.&#13;
|page 7&#13;
about eight o'clock. We went for a walk around the city till it was time to go to bed.&#13;
	The next morning we saw the Art Galleries and Museum and of course saw many wonderful things in there. Saw all the statues you see pictures of in your Ancient History and Latin book. Also saw Glasgow University. We were so fed up with seeing things that we went to see a show in the afternoon. It was a movie "The Battle of the Somme" - and shows the real pictures of the great drive since July 1st. They are the actual pictures of the battle, so if it comes to Canada and you want to see what war is like, see it. It is a rather gruesome thing though. We went to a theatre at night and took the evening train&#13;
|page 8&#13;
for London again. Traveled all night and got to London in the morning. It was raining so we went to a hotel. We saw London bridge and the Tower in the morning. The Tower was worth seeing because of the historic importance of the different things in it and all the old fighting implements it contained. Also saw all the crown jewels and you can imagine what they are like. We then came back to the hotel and decided that we had done enough sight seeing as it was pouring rain.&#13;
	This is all the paper I have and as I was too lazy to go downtown to-night after more, I will continue to-morrow.&#13;
|page 9&#13;
(9)&#13;
Friday&#13;
	It was raining Tuesday afternoon and so was not very good for [sight seeing] so we ordered seats for Razzle-Dazzle at the "Empire." It is a swell theatre and believe me it was some show being about the best now playing in London. There were about fifty in the orchestra and there were hundreds of pretty girls on the stage at once. In the evening we went to the "coliseum" and saw a fine vaudeville show. I sure did see some great shows while I was away. The Royal Alex in Toronto can't be compared with them.&#13;
	The next morning we left for camp again and arrived about&#13;
|page 10&#13;
noon. It was pouring rain and we got soaking wet coming up from the station. It had been raining continuously at camp for three days and there was about six inches of mud around the tents so that we had a nice welcome for us. McMurtry, Shipley, and Keith who are taking the signalling course had to move to another tent and they put three other fellows in who we are not stuck on. They are good and sick of their signalling now.&#13;
	They had quite a lot of excitement while I was away. I am glad I missed most of it except the Zepp raid. The Zepps tried to raid the district&#13;
|page 11&#13;
around here one night and the camp way up all night. The search-lights, anti-aircraft guns and our own aircraft drove them off. The only damage they did was to kill two horses at Folkestone.&#13;
	The next morning at four o'clock there came our order for mobilization and the whole camp had to turn out. It was pouring rain and they had to stay out for two hours. It rained for the next two days and when you get wet here you have no way of getting dry until the sun shines again.&#13;
	I was sorry I could not get any pictures of the trip. It was raining on two days and dull most of the time. Besides&#13;
|page 12&#13;
there are very strict laws all over against taking pictures. I got my Kodak out on the boat trip down the Clyde, as the sun was shining a little, and almost got arrested as the shipyards are there.&#13;
	There were five drafts from Canada came in while I was away so that they will have to do something with some of us as the camp is overcrowded now, and I am among the oldest here now.The ammunition column when all gunners went first in France has been done away with, and so they have more gunners there than they need.&#13;
	I liked Scotland fine, better than London. There are&#13;
|page 13&#13;
not as many Canadians up there. There were an awful lot of Australians &amp; New Zealanders in London, some Canadians and very few Imperial troops.&#13;
	Coming down from Glasgow to London, there were three sailors in our compartment who have been in all the naval battles of the war and they were telling us all their experiences. They worship Admiral Jellicoe. In the Jutland battle, there was a fog so thick that you could not see your hand in front of you. If it had not been for that the whole German fleet would have been wiped out. You remember seeing in the account of the battle in the paper&#13;
|page 14&#13;
that the British thought they sunk one of Germany's biggest super-dreadnoughts but the Germans did not admit it. These sailors were on the destroyer that sent the torpedo, and saw the battleship disappear with a big flash and smoke and are positive it was sunk. Hundreds of German submarines have been sunk but the British do not talk about it until the Germans acknowledge their losses, just to keep them guessing. The Germans never know what happens to their submarines - Jellicoe does. No prisoners are ever taken in the navy.&#13;
|page 15&#13;
	Pay day was the day after arriving back in camp and so my life was saved. I got weighed while I was away and weighed 175 lbs so you had better get rid of all my old clothes. I have not been over to the mess room since getting back as I can not stand the food there after just getting back and having good meals. Well I think this is the longest letter I ever wrote and guess I had better quit now.&#13;
		Your loving son.&#13;
			Gordon</abstract>
  <identifier type="local">ASC19541</identifier>
  <location>
    <physicalLocation>1998-037 / 001 (04)</physicalLocation>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription>
    <form>text</form>
    <extent>8 leaves</extent>
  </physicalDescription>
  <relatedItem>
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Dorothy Stepler fonds (F0170)</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <location>
      <url note="Finding Aid">http://archivesfa.library.yorku.ca/fonds/ON00370-f0000170.htm</url>
    </location>
  </relatedItem>
  <subject>
    <topic>World War, 1914-1918</topic>
    <hierarchicalGeographic>
      <continent>Europe</continent>
      <country>England</country>
      <region>South East</region>
      <county>Kent</county>
      <city>Shorncliffe</city>
    </hierarchicalGeographic>
    <cartographics>
      <coordinates>51.088,&#160;1.142</coordinates>
    </cartographics>
  </subject>
  <accessCondition type="useAndReproduction">Digital copy created for preservation and access purposes. For further copyright information contact : ascproj@yorku.ca</accessCondition>
</mods>
