<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Canadian Capital Markets and Sustainability: Issues, Challenges and opportunities</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name type="corporate">
    <namePart>Gobal Knowledge Ventures</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">Author</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <genre>working paper</genre>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>2002-11</dateCreated>
    <publisher>National Round Table on the Environment and the Economy</publisher>
  </originInfo>
  <language>
    <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <identifier type="local">RPT_2002_GKV_Canadian-Capital-Markets-and-Sustainability-Issues-Challenges-Opportunities.pdf</identifier>
  <abstract>Sustainability is somewhat of a new frontier for the capital markets, where the risks are high, the responsibilities great and the rewards, potentially enormous. There are now growing opportunities for capital market participants to participate and contribute to sustainable development through lending, insurance and investment activities and through developing benchmarks, indices, standards and reporting regimes. The definition used for &#8220;Sustainability&#8221; refers to business strategies and processes that add economic, environmental and social value to shareholders, employees and society.</abstract>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <part>
      <extent>30 p.</extent>
    </part>
  </relatedItem>
  <location>
    <url>http://warming.apps01.yorku.ca/library/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/NRTEE-2002-Canadian-Capital-Markets-and-Sustainability-Issues-Challenges-and-Opportunities.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <subject>
    <topic>Financial and investment industry</topic>
  </subject>
  <accessCondition>&#169; This Work is protected by copyright and made available for personal or public non-commercial use and may be reproduced, in part or in whole, and by any means, and may be further distributed for non-commercial use, without charge or further permission. All users are required to indicate that the reproduction, in part or in whole, is a copy of a Work of the National Round Table on the Environment and the Economy (NRTEE). Reproduction, in whole or in part, of this Work for the purpose of commercial redistribution is strictly prohibited. Furthermore, no right to modify or alter in any manner the Work is hereby granted.</accessCondition>
</mods>
