<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Background Report in Support of ESDI Cluster Groups - CG6 Water Resources</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name type="corporate">
    <namePart>Gardner Pinfold</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">Author</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <genre>working paper</genre>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>2001-10-05</dateCreated>
    <publisher>National Round Table on the Environment and the Economy</publisher>
  </originInfo>
  <language>
    <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <identifier type="local">RPT_2001_GP_Background-Report-in-Support-of-ESDI-Cluster-Groups-Water-Resources.pdf</identifier>
  <abstract>This document summarizes Canadian indicator work and data sources for the Water Resources Cluster Group (WRCG). This includes information on water resources and fresh water fisheries. The report is based on a survey of indicator and data sources that may assist in developing a set of water indicators under the NRTEE&#8217;s Environment and Sustainable Development Indicators (ESDI) initiative. The survey broadly identifies the scope of data and indicators available, and then focuses in on indicators and data that may be of interest to the WRCG.</abstract>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <part>
      <extent>61 p.</extent>
    </part>
  </relatedItem>
  <location>
    <url>http://warming.apps01.yorku.ca/library/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/NRTEE-2001-Background-Report-in-Support-of-ESDI-Cluster-Groups-CG6-Water-Resources.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <subject>
    <topic>Fisheries Industry</topic>
  </subject>
  <accessCondition>&#169; This Work is protected by copyright and made available for personal or public non-commercial use and may be reproduced, in part or in whole, and by any means, and may be further distributed for non-commercial use, without charge or further permission. All users are required to indicate that the reproduction, in part or in whole, is a copy of a Work of the National Round Table on the Environment and the Economy (NRTEE). Reproduction, in whole or in part, of this Work for the purpose of commercial redistribution is strictly prohibited. Furthermore, no right to modify or alter in any manner the Work is hereby granted.</accessCondition>
</mods>
