<mods:mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:title>Jean Augustine interview: National Black Coalition of Canada button</mods:title>
  </mods:titleInfo>
  <mods:identifier>ASC17575</mods:identifier>
  <mods:typeOfResource>moving image</mods:typeOfResource>
  <mods:genre>Educational</mods:genre>
  <mods:name type="corporate">
    <mods:namePart>Instructional Technology Centre (ITC), UIT</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">Interviewee</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:name type="personal">
    <mods:namePart>Jean Augustine</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">Interviewer</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:name type="personal">
    <mods:namePart>Norda Majekodunmi</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">Interviewer</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:originInfo>
    <mods:dateIssued>2014-04-24</mods:dateIssued>
    <mods:publisher>Norda Majekodunmi</mods:publisher>
    <mods:place>
      <mods:placeTerm authority="marccountry">Canada</mods:placeTerm>
    </mods:place>
    <mods:place>
      <mods:placeTerm type="text">Toronto</mods:placeTerm>
    </mods:place>
  </mods:originInfo>
  <mods:language>
    <mods:languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</mods:languageTerm>
  </mods:language>
  <mods:abstract>Recording consists of an interview with Jean Augustine in which she discusses the National Black Coalition of Canada button and the history of the organization.</mods:abstract>
  <mods:physicalDescription>
    <mods:form authority="marccategory">videorecording</mods:form>
    <mods:extent>00:04:30</mods:extent>
  </mods:physicalDescription>
  <mods:note type="funding">This project was supported by a research grant issued by York University Libraries.</mods:note>
  <mods:note type="transcription">The National Black Coalition of Canada, this is a button you won&#8217;t find anywhere now because this is an organization that died in some way. It was very, very vibrant. What we were doing as black Canadians were really trying to mimic um, or to copy the American um, the American organization: the NAACP, the Nation Association of um, Coloured People. And so we worked really very hard in Canada to bring groups together, the black community together. We hoped at the time, the vision was to have blacks all across the country, that there&#8217;d be a national organization through which we would filter social programs, we would do different things. We would advocate on behalf of the concerns of black people right across Canada because what we knew at the time, what we know now is that the situation of African-Canadians wherever they are in this country is more or less the same. We face racism, we have difficulties in empowerment, we have difficulties with our young people; we have challenges. Whether you&#8217;re in Halifax, you&#8217;re in um, Calgary, or you&#8217;re in Vancouver or Toronto; we found that our situations were the same and we felt that a national organization will give us an opportunity to bring our voices together. And of course, the organization lived for awhile with really good leadership. There were people like Wilson Head, Dr. Wilson Head. There was Dr. Howard McCurdy from Windsor. There was Juanita Westmoreland-Traor&#233;. There was Dorothy Wells from Montreal, and um, leadership all across the country. And when we came, we came together in conference, we&#8217;d meet in regions and then we&#8217;d come together. The national conference would be in one city and then move to another city. Very vibrant, very energetic, but of course um, as it says on the button, &#8220;Identity, Unity, Liberation&#8221; were more or less the themes of the work of the National Black Coalition of Canada. As I say, it&#8217;s no more as a national organization; we lost the impetuous for various reasons. One is how do you fund a national organization where you bring people from coast to coast to coast and you know the cost of running a national conference; the lack of necessary funding to support an organization. And also internal bickering around the question of leadership, there was a sense that those people who were in the leadership were a bit elitist by that there were voices that were saying &#8220;everyone who is an executive member is a doctor this and a doctor that [and that] we want our voices as the community to be in this organizing.&#8221; But what was missed was the fact that those people with leadership were also in a position to pay their way or to piggy back on things that they were doing and their professional life so that they could do the work that was so important. And so when we try to work in an office, a national office which we did have, it was really very difficult to keep the office open; to pay staff, to do the communication that was important to do. And so there were all kinds of um, sidebars and different things that somehow the organization had to close its doors.</mods:note>
  <mods:relatedItem>
    <mods:titleInfo>
      <mods:title>Jean Augustine fonds (F0515)</mods:title>
    </mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:location>
      <mods:url note="Finding Aid">http://archivesfa.library.yorku.ca/fonds/ON00370-f0000515.htm</mods:url>
    </mods:location>
  </mods:relatedItem>
  <mods:subject>
    <mods:topic>National Black Coalition of Canada</mods:topic>
    <mods:topic>Blacks</mods:topic>
    <mods:topic>Community organization</mods:topic>
    <mods:geographic>Canada</mods:geographic>
    <mods:hierarchicalGeographic>
      <mods:continent>North America</mods:continent>
      <mods:country>Canada</mods:country>
      <mods:city>Toronto</mods:city>
    </mods:hierarchicalGeographic>
    <mods:cartographics>
      <mods:coordinates>43.773331100000000000,  -79.499138599999980000</mods:coordinates>
    </mods:cartographics>
  </mods:subject>
  <mods:accessCondition type="useAndReproduction">Use of this resource is governed by the terms and conditions of the Creative Commons "Attribution" License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/)</mods:accessCondition>
</mods:mods>
