<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Ecological Fiscal Reform and Agricultural Landscapes:Final Working Group Report</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name type="corporate">
    <namePart>Agricultural Landscapes Working Group</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">Author</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <genre>working paper</genre>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>2001-10</dateCreated>
    <publisher>National Round Table on the Environment and the Economy</publisher>
  </originInfo>
  <language>
    <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <identifier type="local">RPT_2001_AGL_Ecological-Fiscal-Reform-and-Agricultural-Landscapes.pdf</identifier>
  <abstract>The objective of this case study is to determine the feasibility of redirecting some of the governments' taxation and expenditure programs affecting farmers across Canada to meet conservation needs and accelerate/encourage pollution reduction from farmlands.  It focuses on  Environmental Farm Plans (EFP)  and Ecological Fiscal Reform;  Property Tax Credits for Conservation ; and the Conservation Cover Incentive Program through  Case Studies of the  Grand River Watershed, Ontario, Upper Assiniboine River Basin, Saskatchewan and Manitoba, Mill River Watershed, Prince Edward Island.</abstract>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <part>
      <extent>62 p.</extent>
    </part>
  </relatedItem>
  <location>
    <url>http://warming.apps01.yorku.ca/library/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/NRTEE-2001-Ecological-Fiscal-Reform-and-Agricultural-Landscapes.pdf</url>
  </location>
  <subject>
    <topic>Agriculture Industry</topic>
  </subject>
  <accessCondition>&#169; This Work is protected by copyright and made available for personal or public non-commercial use and may be reproduced, in part or in whole, and by any means, and may be further distributed for non-commercial use, without charge or further permission. All users are required to indicate that the reproduction, in part or in whole, is a copy of a Work of the National Round Table on the Environment and the Economy (NRTEE). Reproduction, in whole or in part, of this Work for the purpose of commercial redistribution is strictly prohibited. Furthermore, no right to modify or alter in any manner the Work is hereby granted.</accessCondition>
</mods>
