<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Letters from James Allan to Vivien Beer, September 5th, 6th, and 14th 1916</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name type="personal">
    <namePart>Allan, James R.</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">Correspondent</roleTerm>
    </role>
    <namePart type="termsOfAddress">Captain</namePart>
  </name>
  <name type="personal">
    <namePart>Beer, Vivien</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">Correspondent</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
  <genre authority="marcgt">letter</genre>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>1916-09</dateCreated>
    <dateOther>5, 6, 14 September 1916</dateOther>
  </originInfo>
  <language>
    <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <abstract>Consists of a three letters written by Captain James R. Allan to Vivien Beer, dated 5, 6, and 14 September, 1916. Item includes envelope [from 14 September, 1916 letter] and pressed flowers folded in a piece of paper. Transcription is as follows:&#13;
11.28pm.&#13;
Wednesday-night,&#13;
September, 5th. 1916.&#13;
&#13;
My own darling Vivien:-&#13;
	This is just a message of love &amp; affection as I do not feel equal to a letter. Have had a very heavy day, paying out over one thousand dollars and have just finished totaling up, checking, entering &amp; signing of acquitt-ance rolls and I am pretty tired, but I want to write you, even if only a note, to say I love you &amp; that you are always in my thoughts.&#13;
	My own true love I send you all my love. O how I long for your companionship my ownest dear.&#13;
	The weather has been wet and chilly all day. Can hear the roll of guns in action (even back here)&#13;
#2&#13;
tonight. They have been going steadily for over two hours.&#13;
	Dearie mine my letters are liable to be irregular from now on, but will do my best to write you daily. Brought a book of these letter-cards and when I am extraordinarily busy will send one of them.&#13;
	Lovie mine I want to tell you again that I love you and long for you; for your companionship, love &amp; kisses, and I send a message of love, affection&#13;
#3&#13;
and regard, and beaucoup des 'kisses,'&#13;
	Your own darling,&#13;
		Jimmy&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
5.30pm.&#13;
Wednesday-afternoon,&#13;
September 6th., 1916.&#13;
&#13;
My own darling Vivien:-&#13;
	I have just half an hour in which to write a letter to you so am using another of my "Lettercards"! The Post closes at 6.15pm and I want to get this one away on it, as the Post Office is being closed tonight here &amp; I will not be able to get a letter off in the morning.&#13;
	Will you please excuse the short letter then my sweetheart. I know you'd sooner I wrote this small letter telling you I love you with all my heart, than to neglect writing. Also dear heart it shews [sic] you I am thinking of you. Indeed I think of you all the time darling mine and I like to write to you.&#13;
#2&#13;
	Paid the Signal Company today &amp; have just finished my acquittance rolls. Paid out nearly 5,000 francs (approx. $1.000.). Pretty good morning's work eh?&#13;
	It has been bright &amp; sunny all day; a welcome change after the showery spell we have been having past three days or so.&#13;
	The news today is excellent. Both the French &amp; ourselves have gained ground in the Somme sector.&#13;
	Greece is expected to come into the war almost any day now.&#13;
#3&#13;
Looks as though the war will be over by next Spring.&#13;
	My ownest darling I want this letter to be a message of love and affection. Darling mine I love you so much. Just wish I were quite near to you so I could put my arm around your neck and kiss you &amp; tell you of my love.&#13;
	Love &amp; kisses,&#13;
		Your darling,&#13;
			Jimmy&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
9.55pm&#13;
Thursday-night,&#13;
September 14th, 1916.&#13;
&#13;
My own darling Vivien:-&#13;
	I know somebody who's a dear and her name is Vivien Beer. Poet, what!&#13;
	Now you will say: "Why for all this jollification?" 'Tis 'cause I got two letters from you tonight darling mine and they made me, oh so happy. My sweetheart I like you to be very frank always, 'cause darling I get so lonesome and my heart just aches for you my own treasure. So please continue to be very frank and send as much love as you want to, the more you send the better pleased I will be. Oh I love&#13;
#2&#13;
you so much my sweetheart and I want to see you, to feel your presence, to hear your voice and laugh, yes my darling and I want to tell you with my own lips how much I love you and to hold you in one long fond embrace. I would just love to be able to put my arm around your neck now darling and kiss you. Maybe I wouldn't be happy. I would be completely so my own darling.&#13;
	But I cannot do these nice things and must find a suitable substitute. That I have in the shape of some blue pansies which I am enclosing. I have kissed them all darling and I want them to carry my thoughts and&#13;
#3&#13;
love to you sweetheart mine: and I kissed the right sides too dear, so you won't have any trouble finding the kisses.&#13;
	So having Joan address the envelope was a little piece of mischief you two agreed to, to deceive me, was it? Well it succeeded (until I opened the envelope). So you see it was an agreeable surprise as well. Imagine how pleased I was at having two letters from you tonight, one last night and one the night before. Now darling that is what I call being real good to me. You don't know how it hurts me and how lonely I get when no letter comes&#13;
#4&#13;
from you for a long time Vivien. This is a lonely life at its best dear and you can see how destitute and forsaken a person would feel when a mail arrived and not a single letter on it for him from his sweetheart.&#13;
	But why continue in this strain?&#13;
	Wish you could hear the guns going now Vivien. As a matter of fact they have been going all day, but particularly so since 6.30pm, when our guns opened up in intense bombardment lasting for over three hours. I hear one of our brigades has attacked and gained all it's&#13;
#5&#13;
objectives. The firing has slakened[sic] down now (10.25pm) although some of the heavies are still firing. The enemy artillery have also been very active all day. There has been a large number of our observation balloons up all day. I counted twenty-one at one time and on a very short piece of front as well. They were thick as flies all day. We had also a large number of planes up flying around during the day. The Germans are certainly getting it put over them in this sector alright.&#13;
	Now dear it is after ten&#13;
#6&#13;
and reveille is at five Am in the morning and dear knows what may happen during the night so I better get to bed and have some rest while I can. Will you please excuse brevity for above reason dear.&#13;
	I send you my love and the assurance that I will always be true to you and darling mine I want you to be always true to me and to wait for me. I know you will always be true to me and that you will wait&#13;
#7&#13;
for me and dear it makes me happy.&#13;
	All my love and kisses,&#13;
		Your own darling,&#13;
			Jimmy&#13;
P.S. I save your letters &amp; sent a batch home not long ago.&#13;
	Jimmy</abstract>
  <identifier type="local">ASC17722</identifier>
  <location>
    <physicalLocation>1994-031 / 001 (01)</physicalLocation>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription>
    <extent>7 leaves + envelope + pressed flowers</extent>
    <form>text</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <relatedItem>
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Beer family fonds (F0375)</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <location>
      <url note="Finding Aid">http://archivesfa.library.yorku.ca/fonds/ON00370-f0000375.htm</url>
    </location>
  </relatedItem>
  <subject>
    <topic>World War, 1914-1918</topic>
    <hierarchicalGeographic>
      <continent>Europe</continent>
      <country>France</country>
    </hierarchicalGeographic>
    <cartographics>
      <coordinates>47,&#160;2</coordinates>
    </cartographics>
  </subject>
  <accessCondition type="useAndReproduction">Digital copy created for preservation and access purposes. For further copyright information contact : ascproj@yorku.ca</accessCondition>
</mods>
